<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Recent &amp; Upcoming Talks on Susannah Chandhok</title>
    <link>/talk/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Recent &amp; Upcoming Talks on Susannah Chandhok</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 May 2019 16:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	    <atom:link href="/talk/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Interpersonal Confrontation on Social Media as a Function of Psychological Distance</title>
      <link>/talk/easp/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2019 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/easp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;About:&lt;/strong&gt; In May 2019, I had the wonderful opportunity to attend the 2019 &lt;a href=&#34;https://techandrelationships.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Technology and Relationships Conference&lt;/a&gt;, supported by the European Association of Social Psychology, Facebook, AdopteUnMec, APA Science Directorate, Eris Enterprises, and EmbrLabs. The conference was held in stunning Annecy, France.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During my talk, I described one of my current research projects examining interpersonal confrontation on social media. If you would like to see my full slide deck, please don&amp;rsquo;t hesitate to &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:susac@umich.edu?Subject=slides&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;send me an email&lt;/a&gt; and I would be happy to share them with you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;annecy.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;Annecy&#34; /&gt;
 &lt;em&gt;View from the conference&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Heightened confrontation on social media as a function of psychological distance</title>
      <link>/talk/spsp2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/spsp2019/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A mean tweet, a snide Facebook post - - with every new report of social media confrontation, it seems that the online social universe we inhabit teems with interpersonal hostility. Previous research has considered how online anonymity increases behavioral disinhibition. Yet little research has examined whether people are more likely to be confrontational on social media, publicly and without anonymity and, if so, the mechanisms underlying this phenomenon.  Across five studies (N = 1,124), we examined people?s feelings about engaging in confrontation on social media and in-person. Results showed that people are significantly more likely to confront a stranger on social media (d = 0.43), finding this action significantly less effortful (d = -1.48) and more comfortable (d = 0.60). However, this effect reverses when people consider confronting a close other. Participants found social media confrontation for someone close in social distance to be significantly more effortful (d = 0.95) and less comfortable (d = -1.17) and were less likely to do so (d = -0.96). In summary, this research provides evidence that confrontational on social media is a function of psychological distance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Authors:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Susannah Albert-Chandhok, University of Michigan, Ann Arbor&lt;br /&gt;
Ethan Kross, University of Michigan, Ann Arbor&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Effects of Appetizing Descriptions and General Action-Inaction Goals on Attitudes and Behaviors About Healthy Food</title>
      <link>/talk/spsp2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/spsp2018/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fruit and vegetable consumption is crucial for managing a health weight (Rolls et al., 2004) and reducing risk of cardiovascular disease (Ness &amp;amp; Fowles, 1997). Yet only about 10 percent of adults consume the recommended daily servings of fruits and vegetables (Lee-Kwan et al., 2017). How can we increase healthy food purchasing? Research by Turnwald et al. (2017) found that vegetables described indulgently were more frequently consumed. In the current study, we explored whether describing healthy foods as appetizing (versus healthy) interacted with priming people to an action or inaction goal (a framework described by Albarracin &amp;amp; Handley, 2011) in changing attitudes about an intentions to buy healthy foods. Preliminary results (N = 115) after conducting a two-way ANCOVA revealed a significant interaction of food description and general action and inaction goals on likelihood of eating (p = 0.0258) and buying (p = 0.0376) healthy foods, such that framing the food as appetizing after an action prime lead to increased intent to eat and buy these foods.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Authors:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PI: Susannah Albert-Chandhok, University of Michigan, Ann Arbor&lt;br /&gt;
Faculty Advisor: Allison Earl, University of Michigan, Ann Arbor&lt;br /&gt;
Co-Investigator: Clint McKenna, University of Michigan, Ann Arbor&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;References:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Albarracin, D., &amp;amp; Handley, I. M. (2011). The time for doing is not the time for change: effects of general action and inaction goals on attitude retrieval and attitude change. Journal of personality and social psychology, 100(6), 983.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lee-Kwan SH, Moore LV, Blanck HM, Harris DM, Galuska D. (2017). Disparities in State-Specific Adult Fruit and Vegetable Consumption, United States, 2015. MMWR Morb Mortal Wkly Rep;66:1241?1247. DOI: &lt;a href=&#34;http://dx.doi.org/10.15585/mmwr.mm6645a1&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://dx.doi.org/10.15585/mmwr.mm6645a1&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ness AR, Fowles JW. Fruit and vegetables and cardiovascular disease: a review. Int J Epidemiol 1997;26:1-13.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reed, J., Frazao, E., &amp;amp; Itskowitz, R. (2004). How much do Americans pay for fruits and vegetables?. Washington, DC: US Department of Agriculture, Economic Research Service.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rolls BJ, Ello-Martin JA, Tohill BC. (2004). What can intervention studies tell us about the relationship between fruit and vegetable consumption and weight management? Nutr Reviews,62:1-17.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Turnwald, B. P., Boles, D. Z., &amp;amp; Crum, A. J. (2017). Association Between Indulgent Descriptions and Vegetable Consumption: Twisted Carrots and Dynamite Beets. JAMA Internal Medicine, 177(8), 1216-1218.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
